有一个入口可以直接通向纪念碑
There's an entrance that should lead straight to the monument.
快点，我们快到了
Come on, we're almost there.
我在幽闭空间内，就会呼吸困难一些
Whenever I find myself indoors, I breathe a little harder.
他们要复仇
They take revenge.
有人偷走了尸体
Someone stole the remains.
我的兄弟，无名英雄
My brother. The unknown hero.
你骗了我，奥布拉德！
You lied to me, Obrad!
你说你想报复他们..
You said you wanted revenge on them...
不是这样的！
This is not it!
奥布拉德 · 萨夫科维奇和泽切维奇有什么关系？
What has Obrad Savkovich got to do with Zechevich?
他是孤儿院的赞助人
He's a patron in the orphanage.
还有那个老师，拉杰科..
And that teacher, Rajko...
有他的引荐，萨夫科维奇就会接受他们
He would recommend them and Savkovich would take them.
拉杰科是阿皮斯的调解人，我记得他
Rajko was Apis' mediator, I remember him.
巴尔图将直接从莫斯科前往贝尔格莱德
Bartu will come to Belgrade directly from Moscow.
他们两个将一起炸毁日尔诺夫
The two of them will, together, blow up Zhrnov.
让我们坚持我们对法国的计划
Let's stick to our plan with France.
奥伯拉德 · 萨夫科维奇和我
Obrad Savkovich and I...
对未来没有同样的憧憬
don't have the same vision for the future, you know.
我可以放下一切，但我放不下我的兄弟
I could forgive him everything, but I can't forgive my brother.
你想从我这里得到什么？
What do you want from me?
- 去杀玛丽亚·奥西奇 - 你是在帮我吗？
- To kill Maria Orsich. - Are you offering me help?
帕维里奇最亲密的同事在这个服务机构工作
Pavelich's closest associate works for the service.
你只要发布消息
You just release the information,
政府会立即采取行动
and the service will take action immediately.
在他们处理这些事情的时候
While they're dealing with them,
再组织真正的暗杀
the real assassination will be organized.
他们是多年的情人
They've been lovers for years.
她为他工作，和他做爱，她爱他！
She works for him, fucks him, she loves him!
你愿意做我的朋友吗？
Would you be my friend?
你去找塔尼
You'll go to Tane...
告诉他我今晚不去了
And tell him I won't come tonight.
你在这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
斯坦科派我来帮你
Stanko sent me to help you.
我想成为幻觉的一部分
I want to be part of the illusion.
不能逃避像他这样的人
You can't run away from people like him.
只能杀了他
You can only kill them.
共产主义者绑架了博雅纳，他一个人去救她了
The communists kidnapped Boyana, he went after them alone.
- 混蛋! - 我发过誓的！
- Motherfucker! - I was sworn!
我向他发誓不告诉你的！
I gave him my word!
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
举起手来！
Hands up!
谁派你来的？
Who sent you here?
这很重要
It matters.
我们抓住了萨夫科维奇，泽切维奇在看守他
They caught Savkovich, Zechevich is guarding him.
让我把你介绍给我的战友
Let me introduce you to my war friend.
你见到我很惊讶吗？
Are you surprised to see me?
无名英雄，还有最后一个
U.H. JUST ONE MORE
什么事这么急？
What's so urgent?
你为什么打电话给我？
Why did you call me?
我决定解散南斯拉夫图勒组织
I decided to dissolve the Yugoslav Thule Society.
这超出了你的权力范围
That's beyond your power.
你..
You...
根本不知道我有多大权力
Can't even guess what powers I have.
你觉得呢? ！
What do you think?!
你以为你可以来这里为所欲为吗？
You think you can come here and do whatever you want?
- 你是谁? ! - 我现在告诉你..
- Who are you?! - I'll show you now...
我是谁
who I am.
别再说谎了！
Enough with the lies!
我什么都知道！
I know everything!
但有一件事我想知道..
But there's one thing I'd like to know...
为什么？
Why?
因为你会摆脱我
Because you would get rid of me.
- 我不会的 - 你会的
- I wouldn't. - You would.
迟早，你会把我变成你的玩具，然后扔掉
Sooner or later, you would turn me into your toy and throw it away.
我们都是玩具！
We are all toys!
你和我都不重要
You and I don't matter.
重要的是接下来会发生什么
What matters is what comes next.
那对谁来说重要？
Who does it matter to?
对你...
To you...
变态的怪物..
Sick monsters...
你想杀死我们的国王...
You want to kill our king...
征服我们
And subdue us.
还指望我们感激你? ！
And even expect us to be grateful to you?!
你什么都不懂
You don't understand a thing.
你们都不重要
You're all unimportant.
你，你的国王和你的人民
You, your king and your people
自以为能改变什么的人
who think they can change something.
一切都已经预先决定了
Everything is already predetermined.
结束了
It's over.
你输了
You lost.
那么，这就是结局？
So, this is the end?
是的
Yes.
我没想到会是这样
I didn't imagine it like this.
你有七天时间
You have seven days
离开贝尔格莱德
to leave Belgrade.
永远
Forever.
别去找克劳斯，他已经死了
Don't look for Klaus, he's dead.
消失，忘记这一切
Disappear and forget all this.
我不会忘记你的
I won't forget you.
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第二季 第十集
BLACK SUN SEASON 2 EPISODE 10
干得好，维瑞加
Well done, Veriga.
就是这么做的
That's how it's done.
谢谢老大
Thanks, boss.
- 没人知道是谁杀了他?-没有
- Nobody knows who killed him? - No.
他的印刷厂被放火烧了，他的保安也被杀了
His printing house was set on fire, his security was killed.
好吧
Well...
敬萨瓦科维奇！
To Savkovich!
可惜这杯酒洒了
Too bad for this spilled drink.
马上和日瓦科维奇约个时间
Make an appointment with Zhivkovich immediately.
- 普莎!-什么事？
- Prsha! - Yes?
再来两杯咖啡
Bring two more coffees.
你像两个奶奶一样喝咖啡,
You're drinking coffee like two grannies,
你想要真正的饮料吗？
do you want a real drink?
只要咖啡
Just coffee.
我说真正的酒! 白兰地，葡萄酒..
I said a real drink! Brandy, wine...
拜托，我们要的是咖啡，有什么问题? ！
Come on, we asked for coffee, what's the problem?!
好了，没必要生气
Okay, no need to get angry.
你有没有派人在他家门口监视？
Did you put someone in front of his house to watch?
两个警察，但你知道他不会回去的
Two cops, but you know he's not going back there.
谁知道呢？
Who knows?
也许他现在放弃了，因为没有了奥布拉德
Maybe he'll give up now that he's without Obrad.
丹，他有复仇的使命
Tane, he has a mission of revenge.
他相信他的行动会改变世界
He believes that his actions will change the world.
我不得不承认..
I have to admit...
我对他有点了解
I understand him a bit.
我在努力回忆..
I'm trying to remember...
一句话，一个手势..
A sentence, a gesture...
这种情况会让我
A situation that would make me
了解他的真实身份
understand who he really is.
没什么
Nothing.
很难认出狂热分子，进入他们的思想
It's hard to recognize fanatics, and get into their minds.
我每天都和他在一起
I was with him every day.
我应该注意到的
I should have noticed something.
不要这样对自己
Don't do that to yourself.
不仅仅是切切维奇
It's not just Zechevich.
所有我爱的人，所有亲近的人..
All the people I loved, who were close to me...
我相信我知道他们是谁
I believed I knew who they were.
原来我根本不认识他们
Turns out I don't know them at all.
我甚至不知道我自己有多了解自己
I'm not even sure how much I know myself.
我认识你
I know you.
你一点都没变
You haven't changed at all.
你还是以前那个傻瓜
You're the same fool you used to be.
来吧
Come on.
生活中有这样的时期！
There are such periods in life. Prsha!
- 带两杯白兰地-你说过不要的
- Bring two brandies. - You said you don't want it.
好吧，现在我说我想要，有什么问题吗？
Okay, now I'm saying I want, what's the problem?
哦，上帝，谁会取悦你
Oh, God, who would please you.
我的拉杰克..
My Rajko...
我们袭击 Merdare 附近的土耳其人时抽的是什么鬼东西
What shit we smoked when we attacked the Turks near Merdare.
我记得
I remember.
现在他们说是我们发动了战争
Now they say that we started the war.
他们现在说了很多
They talk a lot now.
这是真的
It's true.
如果我们有更好的香烟，谁知道会发生什么
Who knows what would have happened if we had better cigarettes.
我们也会这么做的，对吧？
We would do the same, right?
是的，一样的
Yes, the same.
来，坐下
Come on, sit down.
我真的很感激你..
Look, I really appreciate what you...
你们俩做的事
What you two did.
你已经净化了我们死去同志的灵魂
You've sanctified the souls of our fallen comrades.
你完成了阿比斯的遗愿
You fulfilled Apis' will.
如果很难忍受，那就不难记住
If it's hard to suffer, it's not hard to remember.
没错
That's right.
你计划的一切，继续
Everything you planned, continue.
警察还有别的事要操心，我会处理的
The police will have other worries, I'll take care of that.
我会让他们误入歧途的
I'll get them on the wrong track.
然后我会组织你们逃跑
And then I'll organize your escape.
去哪儿？
Where to?
你会怎么做，孩子？
What would you do, kid?
你会坐在贝尔格莱德等着被逮捕吗？
Would you sit in Belgrade and wait to be arrested?
等这一切结束
When this is over...
人民会听到真相
The people will hear the truth.
人们从来不知道真相,
The people never knew the real truth,
一直都是这样
it has always been so.
我会在审判时把一切都说出来,
I'll say everything at the trial,
在目击者和记者面前
in front of witnesses and journalists.
人们会听到的
People will hear.
谁来审判你? ! 哪个法庭? ！
Who will judge you?! What court?!
他们会杀了你的
They'll kill you.
腐朽的无政府主义就是这样
That's how it is in rotten anarchies.
我会先组织一次从贝尔格莱德的越狱..
I'll organize an escape from Belgrade first...
然后从州里
And then from the state.
我做过很多次了
I've done it many times.
我们不需要你的帮助
We don't need your help.
为什么？
Why?
这件事绝不能被政治所玷污
This thing must not be tainted by politics.
操，孩子
Fuck, kid.
一切都是政治
Everything is politics.
你最好有什么要告诉我的
You'd better have something to tell me.
萨维奇死了
Savkovich is dead.
你想告诉我是你杀了他，对吗？
You want to tell me you killed him, right?
没关系
It doesn't matter.
伸张正义是很重要的
It's important that justice is served.
我会一直在那里帮助正义
And that I'm always there to help justice.
你很清楚我们的生意停滞不前
You know very well that our business is at a standstill.
但是，这种情况可能也会结束
But that may come to an end, too.
科罗沙克先生愿意进行任何形式的合作
Mr. Koroshac is ready for any kind of cooperation.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know that?
我就是这么想的
I just do.
他告诉我的
He told me.
真不敢相信戈迪纳为塞尔维亚警方工作
I can't believe Godina works for the Serbian police.
我可以，考虑到你们的运动到目前为止是多么成功
I can, given how successful your movement has been so far.
求你了，不要
Please, don't.
如果他对你忠诚，他现在对你会更有用
He'll be much more useful to you now than if he were loyal to you.
我要去意大利
I'm going to Italy.
一旦你这样做了，我们就开始我们的计划
As soon as you do that, we start with our plan.
你的时刻到了
Your moment has come.
别跟我耍花招！
Don't fuck with me!
- 那个疯子? !-是的，哈兹 · 阿索夫
- That lunatic?! - Yes. Hadzi Arsov.
天啊，为什么是他，他把一切都搞砸了
Jesus, why him, he fucked up everything he could.
德国人想要他,
The Germans want him,
我们没有选择的余地，你知道的
and we're not in a situation to choose, you know that.
他们希望你去贝尔格莱德
They expect you to go to Belgrade.
- 我?-是的，你
- Me? - Yes, you.
我有比你更好的吗？
Do I have a better one than you?
什么？
Huh?
达米扬 · 哈吉 · 阿尔索夫
Damyan Hadzi Arsov.
暗杀行动将在贝尔格莱德进行
The assassination will take place in Belgrade.
这是一个明确的决定，我只是不知道时间和地点
It's a definite decision, I just don't know when and where.
但我知道他藏在哪里
But I know where he's hiding.
如果他奇迹般地成功了,
If by some miracle he succeeds,
在到达边境之前把他干掉
try to get rid of him before reaching the border.
一劳永逸地除掉那些马其顿人
To get rid of those Macedonians once and for all.
下注！
Ante!
一切都会好的
Everything will be fine.
- 知音，Pletikosich 在哪里?-嗯..
- Zhivoyin, where's Pletikosich? - Well...
告诉他马上到我办公室来
Tell him to come to my office right away.
- 明白了吗?-明白了！
- Is that clear? - Yes!
这是你需要的所有东西
Here is everything you need.
- 我什么时候走?-快了，准备好
- When do I leave? - Soon. Be ready.
你在这里很安全，没人知道这个地方
You're safe here. Nobody knows about this place.
巴尔图坐火车来
Bartu comes by train.
国王将在车站等他
The king will wait for him at the station.
更多的车辆将在游行队伍中移动
More vehicles will move in the procession.
两辆警车和一辆军车
Two police and one military vehicle.
总而言之... 安保措施很严密
All in all... Strong security.
我们仍然不知道他们会在哪里停下来
We still don't know the exact place where they will stop.
但我们会找到答案的
But we'll find out...
及时地组织起来
In time, to get organized.
我会派人带你去约定的地方
I'll send people for you to take you to the agreed place.
你没多少时间了
You won't have much time.
我得告诉你..
I have to tell you...
我不知道我们能不能把你弄出来
I don't know if we will be able to get you out.
我知道
I know.
我知道你为什么选择我
I know why you chose me.
现在放弃还不晚
It's not too late to give up.
你以为我怕死吗？
You think I'm afraid of death?
- 我们都害怕死亡-我们不怕
- We're all afraid of death. - We are not.
我一辈子都在为此做准备，穆斯塔法
I've been preparing for this my whole life, Mustapha.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
很抱歉我们没有更多的时间见面
I'm sorry we didn't have more time to meet.
下次吧
Some other time.
保重
Take care.
队长
Chief.
我来了
Here I am.
Pletikosich...
听我说，这只是给你的信息
Listen to me, this is information just for you.
不要告诉任何人，明白吗？
Don't tell anyone, is that clear?
是的
Yes.
企图谋杀正在为殿下准备
An assassination attempt is being prepared on His Highness.
他们今天将试图在贝尔格莱德这里做到这一点
They will try to do it today, here in Belgrade.
我知道
I know.
你知道什么？
What do you know?
我是说，我该怎么做？
I mean, what do I have to do?
我们知道是谁
We know who it is.
服务部门发现了他
The service discovered him.
终于有人从中受益了
Finally some benefit from them.
- 是谁?-Damyan Hadzi Arsov
- Who it is? - Damyan Hadzi Arsov.
- 谁?-Hadzi Arsov！
- Who? - Hadzi Arsov!
IMRO 的人渣
The scum from IMRO.
早在1918年我们就应该干掉那些混蛋，但是..
We were supposed to fuck up those bastards back in 1918, but...
服务部门对这些信息是否有把握？
Is the service certain of that information?
这算什么问题？
What kind of question is that?
当然，他们知道他藏在哪里，这里
Of course, they know where he is hiding, here.
他们的警报
An alert from their ranks.
好吧
Okay...
召集人们..
Gather people...
我们在等乔洛维奇，他会带领你们
We're waiting for Djolovich to come, he will lead you.
半小时内准备好，好吗？
Be ready in half an hour, okay?
好吧
Okay.
乔德耶 · 泽切维奇
DJORDJE ZECHEVICH
现在你有名字了
Now you have a name.
你不再是默默无闻的英雄了
You're no longer an unknown hero.
有人曾经说过,
Someone once said,
“只有死人才能看到战争的结束”
"Only the dead saw the end of the war."
我们也会..
So will we...
很快
Soon.
我们早就应该和我们死去的兄弟们在一起了
We should have been with our fallen brothers a long time ago.
但总得有人这么做
But someone had to do this too.
那些无辜的受害者呢？
And what about the innocent victims?
战争就是这样，孩子
That's how it is in war, my son.
无辜的人也会死去
The innocent die, too.
为什么我的生命比他们的更有价值？
Why is my life more valuable than theirs?
波西达！
Bozidar!
你必须活下去！
You have to survive!
- 嘿，博雅纳!-早上好
- Hey, Boyana! - Good morning.
- 没事吧?-没事
- Is everything okay? - Yes.
有什么消息吗？
Any news?
没有
No.
贝尔格莱德警察
BELGRADE POLICE
但是我们已经宣布暗杀国王
But we have the announcement of the assassination of the king.
- 我知道这个地方-真的？
- I know this place. - Really?
一个旧的公社庇护所
An old commune shelter.
你觉得怎么样？
And what do you think?
我不知道
I don't know.
我什么都不明白
I don't understand anything.
现在阿尔索夫和这件事有什么关系？
What has Hadzi Arsov got to do with it now?
达米扬 · 哈吉 · 阿尔索夫？
Damyan Hadzi Arsov?
是的，你认识他？
Yes. You know him?
如果是他，他已经在我们的庇护所呆了几个星期了
If that's him, he's been in our shelter for a couple of weeks.
穆斯塔法把他从马其顿带来
Mustapha brought him from Macedonia.
穆斯塔法 · 戈卢布奇带来了达米安 · 哈吉 · 阿尔索夫？
Mustapha Golubich brought Damyan Hadzi Arsov?
- 为什么?-我没问
- Why? - I didn't ask.
我还以为是马其顿的朋友需要庇护呢
I thought it's a friend from Macedonia who needs a shelter.
如果戈卢比奇带他来,
If Golubich brought him,
那么共产党就是暗杀的幕后主使
then the communists are behind the assassination.
不可能我会知道的
Impossible, I would know that.
- 不合适-什么不合适？
- It doesn't fit. - What doesn't fit?
他妈的！
For fuck's sake!
达米安 · 哈吉 · 阿尔索夫，泽切维奇... ..
Damyan Hadzi Arsov, Zechevich...
穆斯塔法 · 戈卢比奇..
Mustapha Golubich...
是别的东西
It's something else.
你什么时候采取行动？
When do you take action?
当 Djolovich 来到 Glavnjacha，一切都准备好了
When Djolovich comes to Glavnjacha. Everything is ready.
我先走，试着阻止他们一下
I'm going first, try to stop them a bit.
我需要知道这是怎么回事，Damyan 会告诉我
I need to see what this is about, Damyan will tell me.
- 再见-如果他没先杀了你的话
- Bye. - If he doesn't kill you first.
PRIZAD
主教告诉我你有个建议
The bishop told me you had a suggestion for me.
科罗沙克先生是一个非常聪明的人
Mr. Koroshac is a very wise man.
他很懂逻辑
He understands logic very well.
逻辑告诉我你和我..
And logic dictates that you and I...
一起工作
Work together.
托马斯维奇先生,
Mr. Tomasovich,
看看这些东西
look at these goods.
全世界都渴望它
The whole world longs for it.
它就站在这里..
It's standing here...
腐烂..
rotting...
因为我们之间的误会
because of our misunderstanding.
误会？
Misunderstanding?
直到来到贝尔格莱德，我才开始喝威士忌
I didn't try whisky until I came to Belgrade.
这是纯麦威士忌
It's a single malt.
世界上最好的
The best in the world.
你知道威士忌..
Did you know that whisky...
随着时间的推移..
Over time...
随着它的成熟..
As it matures...
失去3% 的质量..
Loses 3% of its mass...
- 叫做...-安吉尔的那份
- It's called... - Angel's share.
是的
Yes.
这就是天使为他们自己所做的
That's the part that angels take for themselves.
就像他们抓走你弟弟一样
Just like they took your brother.
没有天使带走我的兄弟
No angels took my brother.
你杀了他
You killed him.
是的
Yes.
我杀了你哥哥
I killed your brother.
我犯了个大错
I made a big mistake.
这是你为你哥哥报仇的机会
Here's your chance to avenge your brother.
我不能和一个有未结清帐目的人一起工作
I can't work with a man with whom I have unsettled accounts.
这对生意不利
It's not good for business.
你来决定
You decide.
复仇..
Revenge...
或者梦想成真
or a dream come true.
聪明的选择
A smart choice.
你在这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think?
我在找你把枪放下
I'm looking for you. Put the gun down.
别惹我，塔尼
Don't mess with me, Tane.
你怎么知道我在这儿？
How did you know I was here?
大家都知道你在这儿
Everyone knows you're here.
几秒钟后
In a few seconds
整个贝尔格莱德警察都会来
the entire Belgrade police will be here.
你在撒谎！
You're lying!
达米安..
Damyan...
我这辈子有骗过你吗？
Have I ever lied to you in my life?
Golubich 陷害我？
Golubich set me up, huh?
他们无论如何都会杀了他的，塔内
They're going to kill him anyway, Tane.
我只是个诱饵
I was just supposed to be the bait.
来吧
Come on.
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
塔妮！
Tane!
你一直就像我的兄弟
You've always been like a brother to me.
不用了，谢谢
But no, thanks.
我留下
I'll stay.
别傻了
Don't be silly.
我们跑吧
Let's run.
够了，塔内
It's enough, Tane.
我一生都在奔波
I've been running my whole life.
够了
It's enough.
达米安 · 哈吉 · 阿索夫！
Damyan Hadzi Arsov!
我们知道你在里面！
We know you're in there!
出来投降，没有武器！
Come out and surrender, unarmed!
趁现在还来得及，让我把你弄出去！
Let me get you out while I still can!
- 快点!-别逼我杀了你，上尉！
- Come on! - Don't make me kill you, captain!
你知道我会悲痛欲绝的
You know I'd die from grief.
达米安... 别再胡闹了
Damyan... Stop fucking around.
你要走了... 我的 Damyan
You're leaving... My Damyan.
当人们离开时..
When people leave...
阴影依然存在
Shadows remain.
有时记得我，我的朋友
Remember me sometimes, my friend.
为我姐姐报仇
And avenge my sister.
放下武器！
Drop your weapon!
慢点！
Slowly!
放下枪，不然我们就开枪了！
Drop it or we'll shoot!
自由..
Freedom...
放下武器，否则我们就开枪了！
Drop the weapon or we'll shoot!
或者死亡
Or death.
开火！
Fire!
我知道你不正常,
I knew that you were not normal,
但你居然蠢到跟恐怖分子合作
but that you were such a fool to cooperate with terrorists...
你是个傻瓜，乔洛维奇！
You're a fool, Djolovich!
他们陷害你
They set you up.
暗杀是在一个完全不同的地方策划的！
The assassination is planned in a completely different place!
你不仅疯狂，而且厚颜无耻
Not only are you crazy, but you're also cheeky.
我早就该这么做了
I should have done this a long time ago.
带他去格拉夫加查
Take him to Glavnjacha.
我会去审问他
I'll come to interrogate him.
我们走！
Let's go!
- 你想抽烟吗?-是的
- Do you want a cigarette? - Yes.
局长在 Glavnjacha 吗？
Is the chief in Glavnjacha?
不，他去了日诺夫
No, he went to Zhrnov.
他们今天要拆了国王亲自来拆
They're tearing it down today. The king, personally.
操！
Fuck!
Zhrnov.
他们会在那里杀了他
They'll kill him there.
我们必须去那里
We have to go there.
- 斯维塔，转过身去!-什么？
- Sveta, turn around! - What?
开车去 Avala
Drive to Avala.
我们不是要去格拉夫加查吗？
Aren't we going to Glavnjacha?
- 我说了，转过身去!-你确定？
- I said, turn around! - Are you sure?
掉头开到阿瓦拉！
Turn around and drive to Avala!
- 去哪儿?-去教堂！
- Where? - To the church!
下图: Zhrnov
Below Zhrnov.
好的，去那里
Okay, go there.
摄影: AVALA，ZHRNOV，贝尔格莱德南斯拉夫王国
AVALA, ZHRNOV, BELGRADE KINGDOM OF YUGOSLAVIA
- 有消息吗?-没有
- Any news? - No, nothing.
将军先生，已经解决了
Mr. General, it's been resolved.
一切都很好，陛下
Everything is all right, Your Majesty.
它与顶部的主电线相连
It's connected to the main wire, at the top.
当国王激活爆炸时,
When the king activates the explosion,
不仅 Zhrnov 会飞到空中..
not only Zhrnov will fly into the air...
他也会飞的
he'll fly, too.
好了，拉杰克
Okay, Rajko.
快点！
Come on!
嘿，朋友！
Hey, friend!
举起手来，放下武器！
Put your hands up and drop the weapon!
举起手来！
Hands up!
知音！
Zhivoyin!
我们绕过去
Let's go around.
你在这里盯着他
You keep him on target here.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
在这里等我们
Wait for us here.
你们两个跟我来
You two, follow me.
亲爱的王子..
Dear prince...
你欢迎牧师时总是举行这样的仪式吗？
Do you always make such ceremonies when you welcome a minister?
先生，这不是一个普通的部长
Sir, this is not an ordinary minister.
法国正面临选举,
France is facing elections,
巴尔图部长被认为将成为下一任总统
and Minister Bartu is seen to become its next president.
你确定吗？
Are you sure about that?
这对法国来说是最好的
That's the best for France.
但对德国来说不是
But not for Germany.
这倒是真的
That's true.
投降吧，拉杰科！
Surrender, Rajko!
举起手来！
Hands up!
干掉他！
Take him out!
我们走... 来吧，轻点
Let's go... Come on, easy.
- 天啊!-放松放松
- Jesus! - Easy, easy.
来吧
Come on.
探长！
Inspector!
督察，你很棒
Inspector, you're good.
但这次你迟到了
But this time you're late.
结束了
It's over.
无名英雄纪念碑
MONUMENT TO AN UNKNOWN HERO
结束了，斯坦科
It's over, Stanko.
你骗了我
You lied to me.
我一直都很信任你
I trusted you all the time...
你一直在骗我
And you lied to me all the time.
我没骗你 Stanko
I didn't lie to you, Stanko.
你只是不想看到眼前的东西
You just didn't want to see what was in front of your eyes.
你现在看不到了
You don't see it now.
塔妮在哪里？
Where's Tane?
他死了
He's dead.
你又撒谎了
You're lying again.
Stanko 你在自欺欺人
Stanko, you're lying to yourself.
一直都是
All the time.
你也杀了他？
You killed him, too?
是的
I did.
我完成了我的工作
I did my job.
塔宁知道他为什么而死
Tane knew what he was dying for.
你呢？
And you?
你甚至不知道你活着是为了什么
You don't even know what you live for.
你永远不会知道的，斯坦科
You never knew, Stanko.
你只是知道如何服务
You just know how to serve.
你真可悲
You're pathetic.
我为你感到难过
I feel sorry for you.
我也很难过
I feel sorry, too.
你做了一件伟大的事情，塔纳西耶维奇
You did a great thing, Tanasiyevich.
一个伟大的人
A great one.
甚至 Djolovich 在报纸上也说你表现得很英勇
Even Djolovich says in the newspapers that you acted heroically.
我才不管 Djolovich 说什么
I don't give a fuck what Djolovich says.
塔妮..
Tane...
Stanko 是我最好的警察
Stanko was my best cop.
现在这一切都发生了..
Now that all this has happened...
我需要像你这样的人
I need people like you.
哦，操！
Oh, fuck!
如果你需要像我这样的人，你的警察就是可悲的
Your police are miserable if you need people like me.
塔纳西耶维奇
Tanasiyevich...
你知道我们住在哪里
You see where we live.
一切都收紧到了极限
Everything is tightened to the breaking point.
但话又说回来，人们想过正常的生活
But then again, people want to live normally.
抚养孩子
To raise children...
去工作，去尽可能地享受
To work, to enjoy as much as they can.
这就是我们在这里的原因
That's why we're here.
我知道你理解我，想想吧
I know you understand me, think about it.
你将成为我的副手
You will be my deputy.
谢谢你
Thank you.
塔妮！
Tane!
如果你改变主意了,
If you change your mind,
大门为你敞开
the door is open for you.
我杀了一个人..
I killed a man...
谁是我的朋友
Who was my friend.
泽切维奇是个疯子
Zechevich was crazy.
他就是凶手,
He was the killer,
但他很清楚自己在做什么
but he knew exactly what he was doing.
他不会无缘无故杀人
He didn't kill for no reason.
我把他当兄弟一样爱
I loved him like a brother.
我杀了他
And I killed him.
你做到了
You did.
你想惩罚他
You wanted to punish him.
因为他背叛了你
Because he betrayed you.
这是人类的行为
And it's a human act.
至少你知道..
At least you know...
为什么我会伤害爱我的人
Why I hurt people who love me.
对不起，斯坦科
I'm sorry, Stanko.
你是个好人
You're a good man.
你要忍受这一切
You'll endure this.
我会永远支持你，作为一个朋友，永远
I'll always be there for you, as a friend. Always.
贝尔格莱德警察
Belgrade Police
对不起！
Excuse me!
你是安德拉 · 塔纳西耶维奇吗？
Are you Andra Tanasiyevich?
是的
Yes.
我想和你谈谈
I'd like to talk to you.
不可能！
No way!
- 结束了!-裁缝！
- This is the end! - Tailor!
等你听完计划再说吧
Wait until you hear the plan.
船长..
Captain...
请把我排除在你的计划之外
Leave me out of your plans, please.
我只有一个计划
I have just one plan.
只有一个
Just one.
我要为那孩子报仇
I want to avenge that kid.
然后离开这鬼地方
And to get the fuck out of here.
你要为谁报仇，米兰？
Who are you going to avenge, Milan?
你不会的
You won't.
你不会为任何人报仇的
You won't avenge anyone.
好的，队长
Okay, captain.
让我们听听你的计划
Let's hear your plan.
这是普里扎德吗？
Is this "Prizad"?
是的，你需要什么？
Yes, what do you need?
我们需要从南方运一桶白兰地
We need to deliver one barrel of brandy, from the south.
这是为了俱乐部，把它送到那里
It's for the club, deliver it there.
尼娜小姐说
Miss Nina said
把它送到这里
to deliver it here.
给你
Here.
夫人? 好的，卸下来
Madame? Okay, unload it.
- 帮帮他们!-好了，快点！
- Help them! - Okay, come on!
Veriga 一回来就让他去仓库
As soon as Veriga returns, have him go to the warehouse.
让他准备第一批运往斯普利特的货
And let him prepare the first shipment for Split.
- 为了斯普利特?-没错
- For Split? - That's right.
然后..
And then...
为了美国
For America.
你今天心情不错
You're in a good mood today.
我当然是！
Of course I am!
一个光明的未来在等着我们！
A bright future awaits us!
你准备好今晚的演出了吗？
Are you ready for our performance tonight?
我希望它是完美的
I want it to be perfect.
- 我...-她就是！
- Well, I... - She is!
她不会让你失望的
She won't disappoint you.
她当然不会
Of course she won't.
她从没让我失望过
She never disappointed me.
我很期待
I'm looking forward to it.
亚娜！
Yana!
你真勇敢..
You're really brave...
当你终于有勇气来这里的时候
when you have the guts to show up here after all.
你输了，穆斯塔法
You lost, Mustapha.
你会失去更多
And you're going to lose a lot more.
因为你在战斗
Because you fight battles
没有赢家
that have no winners.
因为你什么都不相信
Because you don't believe in anything.
我相信你
I believed in you.
我爱你
And I loved you.
我知道
I know.
我也爱你
I loved you, too.
保重，穆斯塔法
Take care, Mustapha.
亲爱的朋友们..
Dear friends...
我们正进入一个新时代
We are entering a new age.
我的新合伙人,
My new business partner,
丹尼洛 · 托马斯维奇和我
Danilo Tomasovich and I
我们会竭尽全力，让这个新时代
will do our best so that this new age
并没有绕过巴尔干半岛
doesn't bypass the Balkans.
今晚你会看到一个巨大的幻象
You'll see a big illusion tonight.
就像任何幻觉一样,
Like any delusion,
这个是基于事实的
this one is based on truth.
但真相是什么呢？
But what's the truth?
事实是..
The truth is...
我的人生就是一次大旅行
my life is one big trip
到达顶端
to the top.
在攀登的每一步,
And at every step of that climb,
有人潜伏在我身边,
there was someone lurking on me,
不想看到我站在最高处
and didn't want to see me at the top.
邪恶的人
Evil people.
堕落的人
Rotten people
在我背后捅刀子
who thrust knives in my back
尽可能强有力和残忍
as powerfully and brutally as they could.
但我坚持了下来
But I persevered...
违抗..
Defied...
最终，他们赢了
And, in the end, won.
今晚你会看到一个男人
Tonight you will see a man
不管发生了什么,
who, in spite of everything,
生存
survives
而且赢了
and wins.
只有胜利！
Only victory!
绝不是幻觉
Never an illusion.
PRIZAD
逃跑？
Running away?
那看起来不像你
That doesn't look like you.
我没有
I'm not.
趁现在还来得及，我要走了
I'm going while I still can.
但我不明白，为什么是现在？
But I don't understand, why now?
我们设法阻止了他们
We managed to stop them.
我们没有，塔宁
We didn't, Tane.
我们只是..
We just...
让他们慢下来一点
slowed them down a bit.
萨瓦科维奇是对的
Savkovich was right.
一个新的时代正在到来
A new age is coming.
恐怕我们在里面没有位置了
And I'm afraid there will be no place for us in it.
他们没有预测到我们会在里面
They didn't predict us in it.
好吧
Well...
当你出身贫寒,
When you're born poor,
然后你很快意识到，没有人能预测到你的未来
then you quickly realize that no one predicted anything for you.
你必须战斗
And that you'll have to fight
只是为了你的房子
for your place alone.
同样的道理也适用于这个
The same goes for this.
他们的工作就是为我们做预测而我们的工作就是..
It's their job to predict for us, and ours is...
一点也不在乎他们
not to give a single fuck for them.
也许在那里，在那个新世界..
Maybe there, in that new world...
我也可以争取我的位置
I'll be able to fight for my place too.
你会的
You will.
我对美国了解不多但我听说..
I don't know much about America, but what I heard...
绝对配你
totally goes with you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我得走了
I have to go.
你知道..
You know...
- 我从没告诉过你...-别说了
- I've never told you... - Don't.
现在也不要这样做
Don't do it now, either.
贝尔格莱德警察
Belgrade Police
这里真不错
Well, it's nice here.
只是有点寂寞
It's just a little lonely.
好吧
Well...
你知道，它有它的优点
It has its advantages, you know.
我们有很多时间去思考
There's a lot of time to think.
我跟殿下说过了
I said that to Our Highness
当我建议给你一个完全不同的住处时
when I suggested a completely different accommodation for you.
我告诉他如果你想制服一个人,
I told him, if you want to subdue a man,
你不能给他太多时间去思考
you must not give him much time to think.
是的
Yes.
好吧
Well...
幸运的是殿下知道,
Fortunately, His Highness knows that,
尽管我们意见不合,
despite all our disagreements,
我们非常尊敬他
we have deep respect for him.
上帝保佑他
God bless him.
看起来上帝必须努力工作
It looks like God will have to work hard.
为了救他
To save him.
那么，法国呢？
So, France?
是的，马赛
Yes, Marseille.
你一直都知道最后会是马赛？
You knew all along that in the end it will be Marseille?
那么贝尔格莱德是什么? 排练？
What was Belgrade then? Rehearsal?
如果不是贝尔格莱德,
If it weren't for Belgrade,
我不敢肯定在马赛能否成功
I wouldn't be sure of success in Marseille.
现在你是了？
And now you are?
完全是
Entirely.
你会看到的
You will see.
也许南斯拉夫并没有给我们所期望的一切
Maybe Yugoslavia didn't give us everything we expected.
我们都知道我们在一起会更强大
We both know that we're much stronger in it together.
国王很快就要去法国旅行
The king will soon go on a trip to France.
这将彻底改变这个国家的政治进程
And that will completely change the political course of the country.
我希望它能把我们从我们生活的混乱中拯救出来
I hope it will save us from this chaos that we live in.
那会让我很高兴的
That would make me very happy.
我只是想告诉你
I just wanted to inform you
解除对你的软禁
that the decree on your release from house arrest
在殿下的桌子上
is on His Highness's desk.
他将在出发前签字
He will sign it before setting off.
你在思考？
You're thinking?
是的，我在考虑..
Yes, I'm thinking about...
我把那瓶白兰地放哪儿了
where I put that bottle of brandy
你送我上路
you sent me on the road with.
是时候干杯了！
It's time to make a toast!
我希望这是你在巴尔干半岛探险的终点
I hope this is the end of your adventures in the Balkans.
你永远不知道巴尔干半岛的情况
You never know with the Balkans.
帕维里奇先生，欢迎！
Mr. Pavelich, welcome!
谢谢
Thanks.
夫人，先生..
Madame, mister...
这是弗拉多·切尔诺泽姆斯基
This is Vlado Chernozemski.
他会杀了国王
He will kill the king.
1934年10月9日，法国马赛
9th October, 1934. Marseille, France
你出于自卫杀了他
You killed him in self-defence.
你知道那不是真的
You know that's not true.
知音和斯维塔会证明你是出于自卫杀了他
Zhivoyin and Sveta will testify that you killed him in self-defence.
就是这样，就这样
That's how it's gonna be and that's it.
我不想撒谎
I don't want to lie.
好吧，不要
Well, don't.
我来帮你
I'll do it for you.
让我良心发现吧
Let it go to my conscience.
斯坦科！
Stanko!
你杀了他没错
You weren't wrong to kill him.
如果你没有杀了他,
If you hadn't killed him,
我当然会
I certainly would.
你知道..
You know...
泽切维奇可能是个杀人犯和疯子,
Zechevich may have been a murderer and a madman,
但他为正义而战... 他的正义
but he fought for justice... His justice.
直到最后
Until the end.
就像我们一样
Just like we do.
是什么让我们与众不同？
What makes us different?
为什么我们比他强？
Why are we better than him?
我不知道我们是不是更好
I don't know if we're better.
他不是我们这边的
He wasn't on our side.
所以你站在哪一边还很重要吗？
So it's still important whose side you're on?
一直以来都是如此
It has always been so.
谁能想到
Who would have thought
我们这么快就能再见面了 Koroshac 先生
that we would meet again so soon, Mr. Koroshac.
奇迹总会发生
Miracles happen.
我想这就是我们在这里的原因
That's why we're here, I guess.
谢谢你做的一切
Thanks for everything.
你父亲会为你骄傲的
Your father would be proud of you.
去看看世界
Go see the world
如果你觉得有必要，就回来
and if you feel the need, come back.
下午好，先生们
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
我马上就开门见山
I'll get to the point right away.
我邀请你来不是因为我们是朋友,
I didn't invite you here because we're friends,
也不是因为我们有相同的政治信仰
nor because we share the same political beliefs...
他们要求你马上回来
They ask you to return immediately.
我邀请你是因为我知道,
I invited you because I know that,
不管我们怎么看待彼此,
whatever we think about each other,
你知道这个国家的生存有多重要
you understand how important the survival of this country is.
不是因为我们爱这个国家,
Not because we love this country,
而是因为我们别无选择
but because we have no better choice.
就目前而言
For now.
乔德耶 · 泽切维奇 · 博齐达 · 泽切维奇
DJORDJE ZECHEVICH BOZIDAR ZECHEVICH
我们暴露了一些敌人
We exposed some enemies
这就是我哥哥用生命换来的
and that's what my brother paid with his life.
但是还有更多的..
But there are more of them...
他们会给我们带来新人
They'll bring us someone new.
我不在乎
I don't care.
他们正准备进攻
And they are preparing to attack.
影子并没有消失
The shadows didn't disappear.
他们还在这里，在我们上面
They're still here, above us.
所以我需要你
And that's why I need you.
你的国家需要你
Your country needs you.
先生们，是我邀请你们来的
Gentlemen, I invited you
因为我想让你加入新的南斯拉夫政府
because I want you to enter the new Yugoslav government.
一位新同志从莫斯科来了
A new comrade arrived from Moscow.
欢迎！
Welcome!
男名男子名
Boyana.
她接管了贝尔格莱德的牢房
She took over the Belgrade cell.
很高兴见到你，同志
Nice to meet you, comrade.
约瑟普 · 布罗兹
Josip Broz.
你可以叫我提托
You can call me Tito.
我向你们介绍新的总理
I present to you the new Prime Minister of Yugoslavia.
米兰 · 斯托加迪诺维奇先生
Mr. Milan Stojadinovich.
是你的吗！
Is it yours?!
你又回警察局了？
You're back in the police?
我从没离开过
I never left.
敬南斯拉夫！
To Yugoslavia!